WILL AND TESTAMENT
Chunhe.
Liu Chunhe!
Grandma.
Chunhe.
The care home I was in was so comfortable.
If your ma hadn't begged me,
I wouldn't have come back.
Look at this.
I've only been away a year,
and the pickle jar's gone moldy.
Without me, this home would be finished.
Here's a tip, Kiddo.
Dumb women buy clothes.
Smart women like me buy scarves.
They're cheap
and easy to change.
My mood changes every day.
Why were you on the roof?
I was… looking at the sky.
The sky?
Good job.
I told your ma to cut the landline.
What era are we in?
Waste of money.
Hello? Who is this?
Uh-huh…
Gimme a sec.
- Chunhe?
- Yes?
You sent your resume to a training center?
Yeah.
They want a trial lecture next week.
Wanna go?
Yeah.
Hello? He'll go.
Yikes, look at this rain…
They're here already.
My grandson, Liu Chunhe.
He got top-tier at the college exams.
He's waiting for a college offer now.
That's amazing.
Doesn't he have cerebral palsy?
Doesn't mean he's retarded.
Come. Allow me to introduce you.
The core members of my choir.
Thank you all for coming
to celebrate Chunhe's birthday.
Happy birthday to you…
Hope your wishes come true.
Happy birthday!
Cheers!
For our stage, I think that
the park is better than a housing estate.
At least we won't be reported for noise.
What do y'all think?
I'm fine either way. Whatever you say.
Same for me.
As our lead crooner,
I can rehearse anywhere.
As for
performance opportunities…
We'll do the usual.
Go to my son's supermarket,
buy some goodies for friends and family,
then ask them
to watch us perform at the park.
Let's have another toast!
- Let's do it!
- Drink!
Cheers!
He's OK. He has trouble swallowing.
He chokes easily.
It's OK…
Chunhe…
It's all right…
Kiddo…
Can you hear me?
We're home.
Liu Chunhe!
If his mother sees him like this,
she'll chew me out.
Then wait a little longer.
I can keep you company.
What are you doing?
You took my son drinking?!
No! I took him out to eat,
and he had a few drinks.
Didn't I tell you?
He's re-doing year 3.
He's supposed to be studying!
If you get him drunk,
how is he going to study?
Then don't.
What's wrong with taking one night off?
His basics are not bad,
and today is his birthday.
He doesn't celebrate it!
He's an adult now. What are you afraid of?
Chunhe…
Is your son's birthday embarrassing?
What am I afraid of?
Of course, you wouldn't know.
You don't even know
how I survived so many years on my own!
Christ…
Show some decency.
I've been helping with Chunhe
since he was eight months old.
If it wasn't for me, you would've left him
out for the dogs in the trash!
That's right.
If it wasn't for you,
I wouldn't have known newborns
can be abandoned in the trash!
Didn't you
do the same to me?
Bullshit!
It's dead…
My cat's dead.
What? How?
It's dead!
You're an adult now.
You gotta stop this bad habit.
What scam are you into now?
I'm playing a game!
Like hell you are.
Then why won't you show me?
It's my privacy. Why should I show you?
What privacy do you have?
What would you keep private
except for those scams?
Show me!
You're violating my privacy!
What's there to keep private?
Why don't I deserve privacy?
I need privacy, too!
Look!
Chunhe…
In the morning,
in addition to upper limb training,
you have to work on handwriting.
OK. It must've been your handwriting
that affected your essay score.
At 2 p.m.,
he has a math practice test.
It's 120 minutes long.
Uh-huh.
Then heat up some milk for him.
They're gone. They're really gone!
What's on your mind?
I want to go outside.
OK. One minute.
What's up with him?
Hi, everyone. My name is Liu Chunhe.
We'll be looking at a poem today.
Where sunlight does not touch
Spring thrives untouched
Moss in bloom are as small as rice
Like peony shining bright as lights
This poem is namedMoss.
It was written in the Qing Dynasty
by Yuan Mei.
What kind of disease is this?
He must be crazy!
Does anyone know what moss looks like?
Anyone?
Quiet. Pay attention to the lesson.
Go ahead.
It's green. And fresh.
That's great.
Look at this.
After a spring or summer rain,
go under the wall
and the gaps between stone steps.
They're fresh green.
They're tiny and mild
and lush.
Look at this.
Jia Dao wrote,
White dews over sunset gloss
A tree's shadow brushes over moss
Bai Juyi wrote,
Birds perched on red-leaf trees
Upon moss-covered ground
The moon shines in glee
Liu Yuxi wrote,
Moss cover half the hundred-acre garden
Peach bloosoms replaced
By a cauliflower curtain
They're great lines,
but they're just embellishments.
Moss only has a supporting role
in those poems.
Only in Yuan Mei's work
does moss have a personality.
Even in dark places
where the sun doesn't shine,
moss fights to grow.
It may be small as rice,
but it doesn't give up.
It it not self-defeating.
It uses its strength
to live as dignified as peonies.
What a great lesson! Watch this.
Liu Chunhe?
- Yes?
- That's me.
Thanks for coming today.
You gave a great lesson.
We all enjoyed it. Good job! Really.
However, we have to consider
the feelings of the children.
But the kids loved it.
That's right. He loved it.
Yeah, he was great.
But look…
In his condition… He may have trouble…
He is physically capable.
I can't call the shots on this.
Here we go…
There's nothing a bowl
of pig intestines noodles won't fix.
If there is…
Add an extra fatty intestine.
That training course
has run its course.
There's no future in it.
I'm OK, Grandma.
Hey! Pig intestines noodles, extra fatty!
Diao!
Come sit with us!
Goodbye.
Come to the park for rehearsal later.
I've got good news.
I'm not going.
Why not?
Problems at home?
You've disrespected me!
I told you to shop
at my son's supermarket.
But none of you came!
Do any of you know
the importance of a drummer?
The drum is the soul of a show.
Every performer listens to the drummer.
I'm saying it loud and clear…
Unless my demands are met,
I will quit this choir for good!
There's an event organizer in Xin'an
who saw the videos I posted online.
They've invited us to perform in Xin'an.
OK…
They said they'll get the audience.
That means
we don't need to bribe audiences
with goodies.
Isn't that great?
That's great…
- And we get to travel!
- It's a good deal!
- Sure it is…
- Isn't it?
I say.
We still need Diao.
What do we do?
Who'll drum?
Exactly.
We can't perform without a drummer!
That's a huge problem!
Big deal!
I'll find one that'll decimate Diao!
I WAS DIAGNOSED WITH CEREBRAL PALSY
IN AUGUST.
Hi! Feng?
You're not Feng?
A long time ago?
What's happening?
He's dead.
Hello, Zhao?
Let me have the number
for that retired opera drummer, Li.
We need him for a show.
You're a tailor?!
Seriously…
Are drummers so in demand now?
Let's just call it quits.
Wait!
I have a candidate
who's ready right now.
Why didn't you say so?
Who is it?
SEND
I've never played the drums…
Yes, you have.
When you were in kindergarten,
every day at lunch,
you bashed your bowl with chopsticks.
That's different!
How so? It's all hitting!
This is Leshan and Tianfu Avenue.
Please alight one at a time.
And watch your step.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Kiddo!
Do you know how to drive? Kiddo…
- Are you all right?
- Are you hurt?
- Are you OK?
- You should've sat down.
Don't touch him!
Don't take a bus in your condition.
What the hell did you say?!
I told him to sit down.
Why can't he take the bus?
The disabled have no rights?
I never said that. You're overthinking it!
- Apologize!
- Why should I?
Let me go! What are you doing?!
Apologize to him! Apologize!
Don't waste everyone's time!
Who said that?!
- He didn't mean it!
- Let it be!
He didn't mean anything by it!
I'm in a rush!
Let's go!
Eat slowly.
It's OK.
Drink some water.
Chunhe…
Did you practice writing?
Yes. He was great!
He even forgot to eat lunch.
He couldn't even hear me.
He was totally locked in.
In the zone.
I'm contacting cram schools.
When you retake the exams,
choose a college close to home.
Do you hear me?
I'm full.
You've barely eaten.
- Eat more.
- I can't eat this.
- I'm watching my sugar.
- It's nutritious.
When will you tell Chunhe
about your pregnancy?
A little later.
The doctor said
if I don't control my blood sugar,
a miscarriage is likely.
Folks say…
A mom with many children suffers.
Giving birth is a painful endeavor.
Much easier to never give birth.
- That's right.
- Especially people like you.
Like me? How so?
You think you know me?
I was feeling sorry for you.
You can't even tell
when someone's being kind.
I don't get you.
And you don't get me.
We both missed
the chance to get one another.
Whose fault is that?
What are you writing?
A complaint letter.
You think I shouldn't write one, too?
You should.
But it'll lead to nothing, kiddo.
Writing it is a result in itself.
I don't think it's right to lie.
I haven't been studying.
Kiddo… Are you a man?
Yeah.
Then remember this.
A man…
Especially a mature man…
Has to lie once in a while.
Here, choose a drum.
Kiddo…
Just help for a few days.
When Diao comes back, step aside.
You know how hard it was for us
to get a decent chance to perform?
- It's impossible.
- Kiddo…
We need you!
We really, really… need you, kiddo!
- Really?
- Really!
Really!
In that case…
I want a drum kit.
- Don't laugh!
- You see?
It will take forever for him
to learn the drums!
Why do you keep saying that?
Chunhe is nervous enough as it is.
Is that my fault?
You got a retard to drum.
It's waste of everyone's time!
For the last time,
Chunhe has cerebral palsy.
He's not a retard.
Either way, he can't hold a drumstick.
What's the difference?
The difference is that
you've pissed me off!
Stop right there!
All day long.
You said you'd get this guy
and that guy. Then what happened?
You got us jack!
I've put out records before!
And nobody knows who you are!
Are you all right?
Toss it back!
Toss it!
Chunhe! Stop your grandma!
She's fine. She's never lost a fight.
Teach him a lesson.
You're a grown man. Act your age!
Starting brawls like a child…
I wasn't fighting!
I was stopping the fight!
What about you lot?
I have no children. I'm single.
And you?
I'm not calling.
My daughter will kill me.
It'll destroy my family.
Since you know it's wrong,
shake hands and apologize to each other.
Sorry.
I was being rude.
Good job.
ARE COLLEGE ACCEPTANCE LETTERS
ONLY SENT VIA THE POST OFFICE?
INBOX
UNREAD
Can you get rid of this skeleton?
Why do you keep it at home?
It's bad luck.
Your pa and I
have to take a long trip.
It could be a while.
Keeping studying at home
and look after Grandma.
Don't let her get scammed again.
What's the matter?
Why will it take so long?
I'm going to sleep.
- Turn out the lights.
- Are you done?
I'm done. Then go to sleep.
If Normal University accepts me,
can I go?
Not that school.
Why not?
I don't want you to leave the city.
It's only 90 minutes on high-speed rail.
No means no.
If you must go,
I won't pay for it.
Go to sleep.
Chunhe…
My investments have been doing well.
When I finally break even,
I'll cash out to pay your tuition.
It'll be fine.
The weather forecast says
there's 30% chance of rain today.
Let him wear this.
If it rains,
put this on the outer layer.
Chunhe… You're 20 this year, right?
Yeah.
I thought you're two.
- Wash up.
- OK.
Chunhe, look.
I haven't received last month's pension.
So, I asked Social Security.
They said I have to download some code
to prove I'm still alive.
Otherwise…
They'll cut me off!
Old folks these days…
- Old folks these days…
- Hmm?
- Look in the camera.
Open your mouth.
Turn your head.
Close your mouth.
Done.
You're so smart!
That's enough!
Don't push him.
Let him rest so he can drum later.
Let's give it a rest…
Is drumming fun?
It is.
You don't have to hold it like this.
I think it looks cooler this way.
Why is he here?!
I heard you found a new drummer!
Where did you hear that?
Someone who doesn't agree
with this decision, obviously.
It wasn't me!
I just…
A new drummer
was a collective decision.
I thought you got some pro.
Turns out you got a retard.
Don't say that, Diao!
Chunhe isn't a retard.
He has cerebral palsy!
He has no place on the drums.
He can't even straighten his thumb!
His pose is wrong.
His rhythm is off.
You can tell, too, right?
Right.
Wanna see drumming?
This is drumming!
Destroy him.
Good!
Wow!
That's amazing!
Since Diao came back,
- let's have…
- A fair competition.
Right!
Great idea!
- They can play side-by-side.
- Yes!
Let everyone vote on the better drummer.
Yeah!
Don't you say I bully disabled people.
Hello.
You guys rehearse out here every day?
Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday.
Two to 4 p.m.
Inside that pavilion.
How about you?
Can't say for sure. Depends on my mom.
What's your name?
Liu Chunhe.
I'm Yaya.
I like watching you drum.
Add me on WeChat.
You don't want to?
It's not that!
I don't have WeChat.
Then how do you contact people?
I…
I use a watch.
Sorry…
Are you still a student?
No.
I've graduated high school!
I'm already 20.
See ya, high school grad.
See ya.
God!
I sat 'til I got numb,
and you only got a name!
Yaya!
Yaya, wait!
Slow down!
Yaya, why are you holding a street lamp?
Look closer. It's a torch.
You look handsome when you run.
Running isn't all I can do.
I can somersault, too.
Password.
What?
I'd like to buy a farm.
You are leaning on my arm.
How's the wine?
Lovely and divine.
I'm a little hot…
Wash up.
Get out first.
Get out!
At school…
Did you take a sex ed class?
Yes.
Then I don't have to explain.
When a boy reaches a certain age,
it's normal to have reactions like this.
It means your body
is functioning normally.
- If you want...
- Later today…
I want to apply for a job at a café.
- Café?
- Yeah.
Aren't you trying to get work
from that training course?
I just wanna try it.
Saving up for dates?
Saving up for university.
Use this old phone for now.
If you find work, ditch the watch.
You really don't need me there?
Don't move.
Walk slowly.
Don't rush.
Hot latte.
- Pack it up to go.
- Sure thing.
Thanks.
Thanks. Bye. Sir, I can help you here.
Hi…
I'm applying…
For a job.
My resume.
- OK, please wait.
- Thanks.
Boss, a job applicant.
- Liu Chunhe?
- Yes.
How did you get like this?
What I have is… cerebral palsy.
Neurology's oldest unsolved mystery.
We've got a customer.
How long can you stand?
As long… as I need.
How far can you walk?
I can… walk for about ten minutes.
Then…
I'll rest and keep walking.
Show me how you walk.
Look…
A barista's work involves
memorizing coffee types and prices.
You'll handle money,
brew, and wash dishes.
It takes IQ and EQ alike.
I have to make sure you can… handle it.
All right.
All right, then.
Everyone! Today…
I'll be performing the Menu Reading.
Today… I will be serving…
Steamed lamb, steamed bear paw,
steamed deer tail,
roast duck,
roast chicks,
roast gosling,
braised poultry,
simmered chicken, cured meat,
pig stomach,
dried sausages,
assorted crisps, smoked chicken tripe,
steamed pork,
duck stuffed with glutinous rice…
Jarred pheasant… jarred quail,
assorted braised meats,
pheasant, rabbit,
steamed pond frogs.
Betty Botter bought some butter.
"But," said she, "the butter's bitter.
If I put it in my batter,
it will make my batter bitter.
But a bit of better butter
"will make my bitter batter better."
So she bought some better butter,
better than the bitter butter,
put it in her bitter batter,
made her bitter batter better.
So't was better Betty Botter
bought some better butter.
I'm a mother pheasant plucker.
I pluck mother pheasants.
I'm the most pleasant
mother pheasant plucker
to ever pluck a mother pheasant.
I've plucked mother pheasants
my whole pheasant plucking life.
To be honest…
I just want to hire a normal person.
I am… a normal person
with a killer memory.
When did you spot me?
The second I left home.
I knew you'd follow me.
How was the interview?
It's all right…
Not hiring you is their loss.
Experts say that
coffee increases risk of heart disease.
Young'uns have switched to tea.
Cafés have no future.
They'll all shut down.
- Grandma.
- Hmm?
I need to get a bank account.
What for?
- To receive my salary.
- Oh?
You sneaky brat. You got the job?!
Yup.
Liu Chunhe!
You're gonna be rich!
You can buy any clothes you like,
get your own phone,
and go to any school you want!
No, Grandma.
It's not just money.
Having a job means dignity.
It's dignity.
- That's right.
- Dignity.
Exactly!
Eat up.
I'm so happy.
These are happy tears. I'm fine.
I know.
Gimme a hug.
I'm all right.
I'm OK…
You asked for fair competition,
then you smash my drum!
Did you all plan this?!
I swear on Chairman Mao,
I never asked General to smash your drum.
I got too excited.
- I couldn't control myself.
- Like I'd believe that!
Unless you smash that spaz's drum, too!
Diao! Come back!
They're fighting again.
Did you hear something?
See?
Pine cone.
You gave me a fright.
Here.
- Hurry!
- Coming!
Relax. Turn right…
Turn left…
Here you go.
YOUR ACCOUNT BALANCE
Chunhe, you're rich!
YOU ARE THE STAR UP IN THE CLOUDS
I AM THE WEIRDO
WHO TRAVERSES THE RIVER OF LONELINESS
Press here.
Finished.
Not bad.
Good job!
…and then
search the app you want.
You should find the word…
"Install."
What are you doing?
I slipped.
Get outta here!
Feeling shy?
I've seen more men than you've seen scabs…
Grandson.
Hello?
What's he up to?
Chunhe! just finished his milk.
He's reading now.
Make sure he gets rest.
Don't let him stay up late.
Don't worry. I'm taking good care of him.
I got him a rehabilitation appointment.
Tuesday, 10:30.
- OK.
- Make sure you take him.
Don't be late.
- I won't.
- Where's Chunhe?
Chunhe! Chunhe!
- Chunhe?
- Uh-huh?
I'll be home right after I'm done here.
OK.
Study hard. You can do it!
All right.
He's gotta study now.
Bye!
Mwah!
There are still blood streaks on the eel.
Cook it longer.
-All right,
-Take it out.
It'll get rough!
You forgot the scallions?
- It's not done yet.
- Chopsticks.
Chunhe,
do you know the bounce stroke?
It takes technique.
A drummer's pose is important.
You seem so fragile.
You can't even sit well…
We're one chair short.
- And with your age…
- There's a chair in my room.
- I need these, too. I'll go with you.
- Let's go.
I gotta teach you "four" notes
and "eight" notes, too…
You sure you can handle the show?
I've ordered milk, Mom.
It'll be there in 30 minutes.
Put it in the fridge.
You seem to get on with your mom.
She pays my salary.
My current job is full-time daughter.
But I'll be unemployed soon.
Why?
I've been home for a year.
I realized…
We're no longer
what we imagined the other to be.
You've got lots of books.
Have you read them all?
Have you worn
all the clothes in your wardrobe?
No.
I've read all my books.
When someone isn't so limber,
reading becomes an easy pastime.
Don't swipe my mic!
There's no spicy fish
without Sichuan peppercorns.
But you can't throw so much in!
The numbness should have layers!
Dinner's still not ready?
One more dish!
Where's Chunhe and Yaya?
The bedroom.
That's fast!
Where did you find these poems?
Here.
- You wrote them?
- Yup.
- You wrote these poems?
You're a poet, Chunhe!
That's amazing!
This is for you.
"You are the star up in the clouds"
"I am the weirdo
Who traverses the river of loneliness"
That's all?
Yup.
The rest
is still brewing in my head.
I like it. I'll take it.
What's in this box? It's nice.
Hmm…
It holds ashes.
Whose ashes?
- Thunder God's ashes.
- Who's Thunder God?
A stray cat I had.
I picked it up on the street.
It only had three legs,
so it walked like me.
I took it home
and raised it for five years.
And then?
It died.
It's closed.
THE SHARK
Hello?
What are you two doing?
Just getting ready to eat. What's up?
Open the door. I don't have my keys.
What?
Why are you home?
- Time to eat…
- Time to eat!
There's so much…
I'm already hungry.
These are my choir buddies.
Everyone… This is my daughter.
Would you…
Do you… get…
A boner?
As you can see…
I'm a normal 20-year-old adult man.
Thanks for asking that question anyway.
Some people think that
we don't need anything other than
eating and excreting.
What are you doing?!
People like my mom.
Come.
Drink some water. Look.
You're soaked.
I know.
Why'd you miss
the rehabilitation appointment?
That's on me.
I was rehearsing and forgot the time.
It'll be OK. I'll take him to the hospital
and ask Dr. Luo to slot us in.
Who was that giri in your room?
- Chunhe's classmate.
- Impossible.
I know all of his classmates.
I've never seen her before.
She's from another class.
She's re-doing her year, too.
They're studying together.
I wasn't studying.
I haven't studied at all.
I never wanted to redo the year.
Then what will you do?
Go to college!
I applied to Normal University
and I'm working at a café.
You're working at a café?!
- Yes.
- You knew this?!
What else are you two hiding from me?!
I don't know why I left him to you.
- You can't raise him properly.
- Don't yell at Grandma.
It was my decision.
I'll pay for Normal University myself.
It's not a matter of money!
What's the problem then?!
They will never send you
an acceptance letter.
I meet their admission requirements.
Even if you get admitted,
what then?
You can become a teacher?
Why not?
Teachers have to stand
and speak to students and parents.
Can you?
They can't even admit
all the normal applicants.
Why would they admit you?
Well, then…
Who gave birth to me?
Kiddo…
- Whose fault is it that I'm like this?
- Kiddo…
Do you dare say it?
Excuse me, Professor…
If I have cerebral palsy,
would that affect my admission?
Excuse me, Professor…
Hello. This is Normal University's
admissions office.
Our office hours are 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.
Please enter your extension number
followed by the "pound" key.
Thank you.
Your mom's gone.
Eat something.
Can I get a driver's license?
What for? Want to run far away?
If I jump off here…
That's the farthest I'll ever get.
Don't be nervous.
Long time no see.
I'm really in trouble now.
I'm usually fine on the bus.
But I get carsick here.
How do you folks get a driver's license?
By driving.
Did you expect him to fly a plane?
Slow down, kiddo.
Fly a plane…
You're going up a slope! Not off-road!
One vote for Chunhe.
DIAO, CHUNHE
One for Diao…
Another for Diao…
Chunhe…
Why is a whippersnapper like you
hanging out with an old folks' choir?
Diao…
Chunhe…
One for Chunhe…
One for Diao…
Good!
One for Chunhe.
Diao…
One for Diao.
Watch the step.
- Be Careful.
- Lie down flat.
Slow down…
Yes…
The ambulance just took him away.
Get to People's Hospital.
You can't go right now?!
Wait.
Is your business more important
than your dad?!
Hello?!
Kiddo…
I already took the day off.
I'm not going.
I'll wait for Diao.
Kiddo…
You're a big brother now.
Do you want to go see?
Let me help her get to the toilet.
Come in.
Why'd you have the C-section early?
The fetus' heart rate didn't look good.
They were worried
it's placental abruption.
So they operated early.
She hasn't peed
since they pulled the catheter.
No more catheter…
They'll re-insert if nothing comes out.
Don't you touch her!
It's OK…
Don't cry…
It's all right…
Mom's pregnancy…
You knew all along?
Yeah. I did.
Why didn't anyone tell me?
Your mom had high blood sugar.
There was a chance of miscarriage.
The doctor ordered her to be admitted.
We didn't know if the baby could be saved.
Who made me like this?!
Do you dare say it?!
Chunhe…
It was you who didn't fulfill
your responsibilities as parents.
It was your mistake.
I've been paying for it.
I've slowly come to accept it.
I'm still trying to accept it.
Then you keep coming to remind me…
Chunhe…
You're like a gorilla who should be kept
in a zoo cage!
Don't ever think of leaving…
Don't ever be seen in broad daylight.
It would only embarrass
those who feed you.
So then…
People out there avoid me,
they're scared of me, and they mock me.
My mother is the one who truly hates me…
and looks down on me.
I know I'm the dead weight of this family.
I've known that all along.
So, why do you
still pretend to care about me?
You make me sick, Chen Lu.
You're a hypocrite!
Yes, I am!
I despise you!
I don't care about you! I don't care!
Liu Chunhe!
This is your fate!
And mine, too!
I never asked for this life!
Slow down.
Get out and wait.
Get to the curb.
Hey! Why'd you drive so fast?!
You wanna die?!
I hear that the cafe
is launching a new product.
That's right.
We'll soon launch the new
"love nougat candy".
It's made by Liu Chunhe,
our cerebral palsy employee.
Reunion Café is always committed
to charity and social welfare.
We want to help the disabled community…
If it wasn't tax-deductible,
he wouldn't have hired that spaz.
Quiet.
- He doesn't understand.
- What if he can?
How was that?
- Pretty good.
- Any screw-up?
None at all. It was great.
I have a gift for you all.
Hi.
Hello.
You scared me!
I was with my mother at the doctor's,
and I saw a dozen missed calls from you.
I thought something serious happened.
Here you go.
Thanks.
So, you really had no idea?
But when I saw her…
Her stomach was pretty big.
Did you think she just got fat?
Or…
You didn't expect her to have another kid?
I've thought about it.
But now that it's happened…
I can hardly believe it.
That's their freedom.
Whether to have it… How many, when…
They're free to decide that.
Their freedom
shouldn't dictate where I study,
what city I go to, and what I wear.
They should let me be!
Yeah… They should.
So, don't let yourself become like them.
Selfish adults with double standards.
I won't.
Let's go out.
I don't want to go home.
- All right.
- Great.
I need the bathroom.
All right.
Liu Chunhe!
You are the star up in the clouds
I am the weirdo
Who traverses the river of loneliness
The executioner on the bridge
Is killing dreams
The gunshots from the embankment
Killed all desires
I hold a worn-out address
It says…
"This lonely hill's edge"
"Is where I see you at your most beautiful"
But right now
My bubbling heart has become numb
My body
Has become visibly old
I will soon forget
How long I've been trapped
Don't worry.
I see him right here.
I gotta go. All right, bye.
You're home.
- Yeah.
- Hungry?
No. I've eaten.
What is this?
A gift for Mom.
For your mom?
- What is it?
- Candy that I made.
- You made it?
- I did.
You made this!
It's yummy.
Your mom's blood sugar is still too high.
She can't eat sweets.
So beautiful!
Kiddo…
You're so smart!
What's that smell?
My pig's trotter soup!
What's wrong, kiddo?
Chunhe! What's wrong?
Why are you stuffing yourself? Chunhe!
Open up!
What are you doing?! You're crazy!
What are you doing?! Chunhe…
Chunhe… Chunhe…
Chunhe…
Are you crazy?! Open up!
Spit it back out!
- Chunhe!
- Where could be be?
- He can't even walk properly.
- Let's look outside.
I need a break. I'm tired.
If we don't find him…
Wouldn't our lives be a lot better?
Maybe.
But that's another life we can't imagine.
Don't… Don't speak.
When you were being saved,
they cut open your windpipe.
The wound takes time to heal.
Recently,
I've been dreaming about your birth.
Three doctors pressed my belly
to get me to push.
I pushed…
As hard as I could.
I kept doing it wrong somehow.
They said
I didn't know how to push.
All these years…
I couldn't celebrate your birthday
and never got you a disability card
because I'm reminded of those words.
I still thought of it
when I had your sister.
I remembered pushing wrongly.
I was worried I'd do it wrong again.
Chunhe…
That day, I didn't mean
to push you away.
I got nervous.
I was afraid.
This is
my last chance to be a mom.
I don't want any regret.
Chunhe…
I'm sorry…
I'm so sorry. Chunhe…
Kneel.
TALK OVER THE PAST AND PRESENT
AND SPEAK FREALY.
Warrior God… I usually play you.
Today… I am you.
Pass under the Warrior God's robe…
You'll get through
all obstacles in your way.
Tell me.
Why can't people be like cicadas?
Every time it sheds a shell…
It gets a new life.
You can do that.
Kiddo?
Why aren't you asleep?
Does it hurt here?
No.
It's just sensitive to wind.
You've never told me
where that scar came from.
When I… went to Tibet,
I opened an eatery.
I was doing the books one night.
A blade this long
was at my throat.
He demanded money.
I said that money was for my daughter.
I couldn't give it to him.
Then blood spurted from my neck.
And then?
A passing truck driver saved me.
Does my mom know?
I'll take it to my grave.
Don't want her to feel bad.
I'd feel worse if she doesn't.
Still angry at your ma?
She didn't tell you about the pregnancy
because she didn't know how to tell you.
Maybe you think
she's not a good mother
because of her attitude.
But you can't blame her.
No one taught her how to be a good mother.
I had her at 21.
After a month,
her pa left me
for someone else.
I went to Tibet alone
to make money for my girl.
And I was gone for over a decade.
Your ma was already 15 when I came home.
All these years,
she hasn't called me ma once.
I don't blame her.
It was my fault. When she most needed me…
I think…
You're great…
- Grandma.
- Hmm?
Do you think…
My sister would want
a brother like me?
By the way…
While you were in the hospital,
a delivery came for you.
- It's mine?
- Yup.
NORMAL UNIVERSITY ACCEPTANCE LETTER
Grandma…
Grandma!
What's wrong?
- Grandma!
- What's wrong?
Look…
Normal University accepted me.
Chunhe!
You can be a teacher now!
Normal University!
Mr. Liu!
"Dear Liu Chunhe."
Our school has decided to admit you
into the Department of Chinese Literature.
Please report to the school
on August 27, 2023,
"with your admission letter for admission."
Congratulations, Mr. Liu!
OUTPATIENT MEDICAL RECORDS
MASSAGE IS EFFECTIVE
COULD NOT FIND MIRACLE WORKER
REJECTED BY CHUNHE
SURGERY
Pass out the food.
- Hurry!
- You guys eat first.
I need the bathroom! Go to the toilet.
I told you so!
Hey, I'm warning you!
Impersonating the police is a crime!
Why the hell should I calm down?!
Come again?
Grandma's coming. Let's go.
Grab your stuff.
Whose stuff is this?
Wait, everyone.
- I have an announcement.
- What?
The police just called me.
The organizer in Xin'an is a con artist.
He was arrested yesterday.
What about our performance?
It's canceled.
However…
Since I am experienced in being scammed,
I was extra careful this time.
I haven't sent our money over.
So, our train fare is our only loss.
That's a silver lining, right?
I can return the money to you all now.
I don't know where you got this number.
I'm no sucker!
What group?
This way, please.
-The stars of Shuchuan Bus Group's
-Thanks.
Love is Barrier-free Town Hall
has arrived!
Let's give them a hand!
SHUCHUAN BUS GROUP'S LOVE
IS BARRIER-FREE TOWN HALL
A month ago,
we received a letter from Mr. Liu.
Our executives were alerted
and they immediately ordered
the driver to undergo training.
We promise to improve service quality
to provide
safe travels for every passenger.
Thank you, Secretary Wang,
for setting a positive example.
We have arranged some goodies
for Mr. Liu and his family.
Friends, this is meeting of hearts
and a transmission of love.
Let us welcome Mr. Liu
to take the stage.
Please, Chunhe.
Let us welcome Mr. Liu to take the stage
and say a few words.
Chunhe…
I thought I was called to this hearing
because my complaint worked.
I thought
I'd see opposing sides
debate the issues.
Unfortunately,
that's not the case.
I see three bags of goodies
though I choke whenever I eat.
You probably can't imagine
what that feels like.
I'm not upset
nor am I in pain
because I'm used to it.
Instead, I feel a little fear.
I fear I can't even do a simple task.
And I fear that
if those who do these tasks for me
are gone one day…
I may not be able to carry on.
I've asked my grandma…
I've asked my parents…
And I've asked my doctor…
Why does it have to be me?
I didn't get an answer.
I'll never get an answer.
In the crowd,
I've met all kinds of gaze.
Gazes of pity…
Gazes of fear…
Even gazes of disgust…
But I've rarely
seen a gaze
that dared to stare at me
and tell me I'm one of them.
These old folks showed me that gaze.
When I see that
they don't know mobile payment…
Or identity authentication…
I feel like I've found my people.
Do you know the bucket theory?
A barrel's volume
is determined by its shortest plank.
To this world,
we are that short plank.
I just want you to see…
No matter how small
or broken I am,
I am what I am.
The meaning of happiness
should include every one of us.
HOPE
- Grandma.
- Hmm?
You taught me
mature men
should learn to lie.
It's my turn to teach you something.
A mature woman
should learn to be honest to herself.
- Grandma.
- Hmm?
After you take me to school,
I'll buy you a meal at the cafeteria.
All right.
And then…
Buy yourself a train ticket
and go wherever you want.
Go look around. Go have some fun.
Let me walk
the rest of my path my way.
All right?
All right.
It's beautiful. It is.
My friend, you are going afar tonight
Take this drink
Forget the sorrows of traveling alone
To the ends of the world
Get drunk until the end of time
Once you drift away today
You may never stop again
Let us raise our glasses
Cheers, my friend
My friend, you are going afar tonight
Take this drink
The sky is blue and free
You long for it badly
I only hope those carefree days
Will cease being a luxury someday
Let us raise our glasses again
Cheers, my friend
My friend, you are going afar tonight
Take this drink
The green fields have no end
Much like our childhood gaze
When I think of you wandering the world
Just to take control of your life
I suddenly can no longer
Hold back my tears
Cheers, my friend
Right now…
The Oldies Choir
would like to perform "My Beloved".
I want to steal a lookie-doo at him
While pretending
To be looking at vase of flower
All I can do is steal a lookie-doo at him
Like I'm looking at a painting
If he knows, he might mock my foolishness
So, I can only avert my gaze
Though I'd like to say one thing to him
She's standing there right next to him
I want to steal a lookie-doo at him
While pretending
To be looking at vase of flower
All I can do is steal a lookie-doo at him
Like I'm looking at a painting
If he knows, he might mock my foolishness
So, I can only avert my gaze
Though I'd like to say one thing to him
She's standing there right next to him